Nathaniel Payne - Curriculum Vitae

LinkedIn | GitHub | CodeWars

Summary

Hi, I'm Nathaniel, a South-West UK based, enthusiastic software developer at the start of a new career!

For the last four years, I've been working in Bristol as a Recruitment Consultant; a specialist in introducing full stack software developers to SMEs across the South West. Working in this role gave me an opportunity to speak with developers about their roles on a daily basis, and saw me regularly attending events and meetups in Bristol; it was this exposure to the software industry that inspired me to pursue a career in development.

Currently, I'm enrolled onto the 'Full Stack Track' with iO Academy in Bath. I'll be graduating on 18th June 2021 and available to start a new role from Monday 21st June.

Projects

Typescript Web Application - iO Academy Aptitude Test

Live Version - GitHub Repo

This project was part of the course I took with iO Academy. We were tasked, as two separate, agile teams of 8, to add functionality to a legacy application written in Typescript. I worked on implementing Bootstrap modals throughout the app, adding functionality to the user journey experienced whilst completing the test (using Typescript), and some minor bug fixes.

OOP PHP Web Application - 'SOLID Properties'

Live Version - GitHub Repo

This was another group project where I and my team (8 in total) were required to design an application from the ground up that adhered to SOLID principles. We designed a class structure/architecture as a team and worked to implement this using PHP with a minimal front-end, constructed with HTML5 and CSS (using SASS, with a Gulp compiler).

Front-End Todo App - Personal Project

Live Version - GitHub Repo

This is a personal project that I started in my spare time whilst early on in my time with iO Academy. Currently, it's written in Vanilla JS with Handlebars and fairly basic HTML and CSS. I hope to implement new tools, technologies and techniques as my knowledge grows.

Experience

Recruitment Consultant progressing to Principal Recruitment Consultant

Experis/People Source Consulting (February 2018 – March 2021)

Specialising in the introduction of Software Developers (primarily full-stack .NET/Java/Javascript) into high-growth technology SMEs in the South West, I was largely responsible for generating my own business and delivering upon those requirements. I initially joined Experis in February 2018 before our team was TUPE'd over to People Source in September that year.

In this role I took it upon myself to learn some of the technical skills that I was recruiting for (including Javascript, CSS, HTML, Git etc) in my spare time.

Prior Opus Recruitment Solutions - Recruitment Consultant (April 2017 – January 2018)

Experience JSM Associates - Recruitment Consultant (May 2016 – April 2017)

Vado - Retail Sales Office Coordinator (January 2016 – May 2016)

Onward Travel Solutions Ltd - Duty Manager (March 2014 – October 2015)

Onward Travel Solutions Ltd - Sales Administrator Team Captain (August 2012 – March 2014)

The Oak House Restaurant - Assistant Manager (1st January 2011 – 23rd June 2012)

The Oak House Restaurant - Bar Supervisor (2009 – 1st January 2011)

Education Trainee Software Developer

iO Academy (March 2021 - Present)

In March 2021 I left recruitment and began full-time training as a software developer with iO Academy in Bath, on their 'Full Stack Track' course.

During this 16-week course I have been furthering my understanding of software development processes and deepening my technical, and professional, skills by working on production standard projects using a wide range of industry standard tools.

I have also attained Certified Scrum Master status as part of the course.

Bridgwater College (2007 – 2009)

National Diploma BTEC in Media Production for TV/Film

Kings of Wessex Academy and Sixth Form College (2003 – 2007)

AS Level Psychology GCSE Mathematics GCSE English AS Level Physics GCSE Science GCSE I.T.

AS Level Photography GCSE Religious Studies

Interests

I am a huge music fan, and regularly attend whatever gigs/events I am able to, as well as playing and practising the guitar. I read often, and mostly enjoy sci-fi/fantasy epics.

I am currently reading Dune (Frank Herbert), and Clean Code (Robert C. Martin).

My other hobbies/interests include running, video and tabletop role-playing games and, like many others in the past year, I've tried out a little gardening and DIY.